Guide to the Burning Water Archive ca.1962-1968 MSS.007
Fales Library and Special Collections
Burning Water Archive
ca. 1962-1968
Fales Library and Special Collections
Burning Water
MSS.007
0.25 Linear Feet in one half manuscript box.
The Burning Water Archive is a collection of correspondence to the editors, Edward Kissam and Paul Boorstin, and issues 1-5 of the journal.
Provenance
The Burning Water Archive was acquired in 1969.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Scope and Content Note
The Burning Water Archive is a collection of correspondence to the editors, Edward Kissam and Paul Boorstin, from 1962 to 1968. Collection highlights include letters written by Carol Bergé, Robert Bly, Ted Enslin, Clayton Eschleman, and Gary Snyder.
Arrangement
The correspondence in the collection is arranged alphabetically. The issues of the journal are organized chronologically.
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence and Issues of Burning Water
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Art, Modern |y 20th century |v Periodicals.; Manuscripts for publication.; Literature, Experimental |x Periodicals.; New York (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Avant-garde (Aesthetics); Postcards.; Correspondence.; Small presses -- New York (State) -- New York.; American literature -- 20th century.; Authors, American -- 20th century.; Bly, Robert; Bergé, Carol, 1928-; Snyder, Gary, 1930-; Enslin, Theodore; Eshleman, Clayton
- Series I: Correspondence and Issues of Burning Water
  Scope and Contents note
  Series 1 contains one box of correspondence to the editors, Edward Kissam and Paul Boorstin between 1962-1968. Noted correspondents include Carol Bergé, Robert Bly, Ted Enslin, Clayton Eschleman, and Gary Snyder. Series 1 also contains issues 1-5 of Burning Water.
  - Carol Bergé, Robert Bly, George Bowering, 1962-1964; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cardona-Hine, Alvan Choudhury, Malay Roy - Defense Fund, John Willian Corrington, 1962-1964; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Maurice English, D.J. Enright, Ted Enslin, Clayton Eshleman, 1962-1965; undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Roy Fisher, Frederic A. Franklyn, John Haines, William Harmon, George Hitchcock, Anselm Hollo, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ron Johnson, Robert Kelly, Howard McCord, James Merrill, James Ryan Morris, 1963-1965; undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Margaret Randall, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gary Snyder, John Tagliabue, Anne Waldman, Peter Wild, Jonathan Williams, and Miller Williams., 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Issues 1-3 of Burning Water, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Issues 4-5 of Burning Water, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)